John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Corporate Structure, RG 1 FA1793
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Board of Trustees, 1950-2019; 1; 33.99 Cubic Feet 87 letter document boxes and 5 half-letter boxes
  - Committees, 1950-2019; 3; 18.42 Cubic Feet 47 letter document boxes and 3 half-letter boxes
    - Distribution Committee, 1986-1997; 4
      - Memo re: Elementary and Secondary Education Proposals, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
        Outlines the categories of the grant requests and provides guidelines for distribution.
      - Memos re: Community Foundations and Donor-advised funds, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
        Memos from C.C. Gibson and Lee Hills re: experimenting with making grants to community foundations.
    - Finance Committee, 1976-2001; 5
      The files consist of meeting minutes, correspondence to investment managers regarding investments and portfolios, and balance sheets.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Minutes of Investment Committee meetings, 4/20/76 and 6/21/76, discussing financial forecast and KF investments.
      - Memo re: Management Portfolio, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Memo and graphs showing results of management portfolio for KF investment manager, Bache Stuart Halsey Shields.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1978 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Minutes discuss economic outlook and investment strategies.
      - Correspondence re: Investment Portfolio, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Letters between First National Bank of Akron, Charles Clark and E.J. Thomas discussing performance of KF's portfolio.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Minutes discuss investment performance and strategies.
      - Balance Sheets, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Assets, Liabilities and Fund Balance.
      - General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Financial projections, accounting procedures for private foundations, progress report on office procedures, and memos re: insurance.
      - General Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Meeting minutes, memos re: hiring of financial consultant, summary of office and grant procedures, investment data, notes on meetings with banks.
      - General Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Financial summary of assets, graphs of KF portfolio performance, James L. Knight's comments on portfolio performance.
      - General Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Meeting minutes and memos re: insider trading, and KF investment performance.
      - Meetings and Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Contains Investment Manager Update comparing 1987 performance results with those for the previous year; corres. and memo re. investment objectives; and notes from meetings. Correspondents include Creed Black, David Catrow, Gordon Heffern (chairman).
      - Investment Management Survey, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Report by Investment Management Network includes overview of KF's investment activities.
      - Notes from Investment Committee Meeting, 1989 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Minutes of meeting re: status of KF investments.
      - Meetings and Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Meeting materials (review of investment activity), memo on trustee compensation.
      - Finance Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        1989 expenses, financial report, reports on investments, pension plan, excess holdings, materials for meetings, notes from special finance committee meeting, 12/90.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Minutes re: investments, investment management.
      - Compensation report, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Report drafted by Gordon Heffern; compensation survey of other foundations.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Minutes re: John S. Knight Estate, KF investment diversification, investment managers.
      - Investment Management Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        Reports and memos from Tim Crowe re: KF investment status and strategies.
      - Meeting Materials, 1992 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Materials discussed at Finance Committee Meeting re: 1991 audited financial statement, portfolio information, fixed income review, reports from investment managers, and ten year plan.
      - Meeting Materials, 1992 August 31 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        Materials for Finance Committee Meeting (canceled due to Hurricane Andrew).
      - Meeting Materials, 1992 November 23 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        Materials for Finance Committee Meeting re: actual administrative expenses 1992, 1993 budget for administrative expenses, portfolio performance report, investment managers, matching gifts for employee contributions. NOTE: Discovered to be MISSING 8/15/2006 by LCP.
      - Meeting Materials, 1993 March 4-5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        Topics covered include portfolio overview, audit results, investment managers, balance sheets, investment performance.
      - General Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        Memos and reports from Tim Crowe re: KF investments, Knight Ridder Inc. outlook, and Finance Committee meeting highlights.
      - Meeting Materials, 1993 June 1-2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        Topics covered include fixed income investments, portfolio performance results, asset allocation, and general administrative issues.
      - Meeting Materials, 1993 September 8-9 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        Topics covered include portfolio review, market report, investment management, administrative issues, June financial statements, and minutes of June Finance Committee Meeting.
      - Meeting Materials, 1993 November 29-30 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        Topics covered include 1993 administrative expense review, 1994 administrative expense budget, economic and market review, portfolio review, investment management, retirement fund performance review, Knight-Ridder information, October 1993 financial statements, reference articles.
      - General Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Memos from Tim Crowe re: investment managers and investment decisions.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1994 March 3-4 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        Topics covered include investment objectives and policies, 1991 diversification plan, portfolio composition and performance, investment managers, Knight-Ridder holdings, economic outlook, asset allocation, cost analysis, investment guidelines, chronology of investment events, manager performance tables, portfolio characteristics, reference.
      - Supplemental Meeting Materials, 1994 March 3-4 (Box 3, Folder 3)
        Audited 1993 financial statements and footnotes, performance data for managers, real estate investment information, expense schedules for investments, and stock information.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1994 May 24-25 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        Topics covered include portfolio status report, investment manager reports, Knight-Ridder information, and minutes of March 3-4, 1994 meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1994 August 30-31 (Box 3, Folder 5)
        Topics covered include market report, portfolio status report and July financial statements, financial report of first half of 1994, fixed income investment strategy, investments, budget review, minutes of May 24-25, 1994 meeting, Knight-Ridder information, and administrative issues.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1994 November 28-29 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        Topics covered include portfolio status report and September financial statements, market report, James L. Knight Trust information/resolution, 1994 administrative expense review, 1995 administrative budget, investments report, 1994 Foundation contribution to 403 (b) plan, compensation and pension issues, amendments to pension plan/resolutions, minutes of August 1994 meeting, and Knight-Ridder info.
      - Minutes of Special Finance Committee Meeting, 1994 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        Minutes re: James L. Knight Estate.
      - Meeting Materials, 1995 March 2-3 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Topics covered include James L. Knight Estate information, review of current investments, asset allocation, investment managers, portfolio review, 1994 financial statements, and Knight-Ridder stock information. Also includes draft minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1995 June 19 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        Topics covered include market overview, portfolio schedules, performance schedules, investment managers, grant spending/tax rate strategy information, 403 (B) plan amendments, James L. Knight Estate data, Knight-Ridder information, parental leave policy, minutes of March 2-3, 1995 meeting, and reference.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1995 September 5 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Topics covered include portfolio summary report, market overview, KF staff organization and resumes, Cambridge Associates background, administrative expense budget review, 1995 administrative expense budget, Knight-Ridder stock information, June 1995 financial statements, minutes from 6/19/95 meeting, and reference materials.
      - Meeting Materials, 1995 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        Topics covered include pension plan issues, 1995 administrative expense review, 1996 administrative expense budget, 1995 and 1996 program initiatives review, grant spending guidelines, investment policy, portfolio review, status report on audits, Knight-Ridder information. Also included are minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting Materials, 1996 March 18 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        Topics covered include 1995 audited financial statements, portfolio summary report, market and economic data, asset allocation schedules, Knight-Ridder information, proxy voting practices, compensation and benefits study, defined benefit pension plan documents, duties of Administrative Committee, Summary Plan Document, Investment Participation data, Defined contribution (403b) pension plan documents, including 403(b) Vanguard service agreement. Vanguard Fiduciary Trust Company.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1996 June 17 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        Minutes of 3/18/96 meeting, investment discussion, investment managers, treasurer's report to the board, portfolio summary report, financial statements, Knight-Ridder information, and administrative expense budget.
      - Meeting Minutes of Finance Committee and HR and Admin. Subcommittee Meeting, 1996 September 16-17 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        Minutes of Finance Committee Meeting 6/17/96, portfolio status report, employee assistance program.market update, compensation and benefits survey.
      - Meeting Minutes of Finance Committee and HR and Admin. Subcommittee Meeting, 1996 December 9 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Minutes of HR/Admin. Subcommittee meeting re: retirement benefits, report by HR manager, technology plan and 1997 budget impact, review of 1996 and 1997 administrative budget. Minutes of Finance Committee meeting re: economic and market data portfolio status report, real estate investments, reference articles, 1996 financial statements.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1997 March 17 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Minutes of 3/17/97 meeting of the finance committee, and the human resources and administration subcommittee and the pension plan administration committee. Includes agenda, status reports, investment discussion, portfolio summary report, financial statements, and a report on the pension plans.
      - Finance Committee Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1997 May-June (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Minutes of the special meeting held in Boston re: Absolute Return investment strategies on May 16, 1997. Minutes and materials for the finance committee meeting held in San Jose, California on June 16, 1997.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1997 September 15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        Minutes of 6/17/97 meeting, portfolio status report, financial statements, recent events, real estate investing (Cambridge Associates), Knight Foundation's real estate investment portfolio, economic and market update (Cambridge Associates). Also includes HR and Administration Subcommittee meeting materials.
      - Meeting Minutes and Materials, 1998 March 16 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        Minutes of 12/8/97 meeting of the Finance Committee and Treasurer's Report; includes: recent events, portfolio summary report (December 1997), asset allocation discussion, active vs. passive investing, large cap domestic equity manager review, Ernst and Young audit report, audited 1997 financial statements, custodian bank review and project proposal from Cambridge Associates, economic and market update from Cambridge Associates, Pension meeting (report on 403(b) plan, report on defined benefit pension plan). Also included are minutes of the Defined Benefit and Defined Contribution Pension Plans' Committee Annual meetings.
      - Finance Committee Meeting, 1998 June 14 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Materials for the Finance Committee Meeting of 6/14/98, held in Grand Forks, ND. Includes the minutes of the Finance Meeting of 3/16/98, recent events, a portfolio summary report, a report and recommendations on custodian bank review, an economic and market update by Cambridge Associates, and first quarter 1998 financial statements.
      - Finance Committee Meeting, 1998 September 14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        Materials for the Finance Committee Meeting of 9/14/98, held in Miami, FL. Includes the minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of 6/14/98, recent events, a portfolio summary report, an economic and market update by Cambridge Associates, a grant spending study, a securities lending program by Mellon Bank, and the July, 1998 financial statements.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1998 December 7 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        Meeting Minutes of the Finance Committee, 12/7/98, held in Miami, FL. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of September 14, 1998, recent events, a portfolio summary report, a market update by Cambridge Associates, a financial statement, and a memo from Tim Crowe to Rolfe Neill re: risk management and rogue trading.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1999 March 15 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        Meeting Minutes of the Finance Committee, 3/15/99, held in Miami, FL. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of December 7, 1998, recent events, a presentation by Everest Capital, Ltd., a portfolio summary report, a market update by Cambridge Associates, 1998 year in review, and financial statements for the years ending 1998 and 1997.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1999 June 14 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Meeting Minutes of the Finance Committee, 6/14/99 held in Macon, GA. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meetiing of March 15, 1999, recent events, portfolio summary reports, staff changes, a market update by Cambridge Associates, financial statements, and a presentation by Lauren Fine, newspaper industry analyst for Merrill Lynch.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1999 September 13 (Box 6, Folder 4)
        Materials for the meeting of the Finance Committee held 9/13/1999, including minutes of the 6/14/99 meeting, second quarter 1999 portfolio summary report, biography of Ed McKelvey, market update by Cambridge Associates, treasury inflation protected securities, and second quarter 1999 financial statements.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1999 December 6 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        Meeting Minutes of the Finance Committee, 12/6/1999, held in Miami, FL. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of September 13, 1999, recent events, third quarter 1999 portfolio summary report, market update by Cambridge Associates, investing in Asia, and third quarter 1999 financial statements.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 March 13 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        Meeting Minutes of the Finance Committee, 3/13/2000, held in Miami, FL. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of December 6, 1999, recent events, 1999 portfolio summary report, market update by Cambridge Associates, David Swensen--Chief Investment Officer, Yale University, asset allocation, audited 1999 financial statements and management report.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        Meeting Minutes of the Finance Committee, 6/12/2000, held in Akron, OH. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of March 13, 2000, recent events, first quarter 2000 portfolio summary report, market update by Cambridge Associates, Oak Associates highlights, Ernst and Young bid for outsourced tax work, first quarter 2000 financial statements.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 September 10 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        Meeting Minutes of the Finance Committee, 9/10/2000, held in Miami, FL. Includes minutes of the Finance Committee meeting of June 12, 2000, recent events, action items, portfolio summary report (second quarter 2000), market update by Cambridge Associates, and financial statements (second quarter 2000).
      - Committee Meeting - Investment Presentation Book, 2000 December 4 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        Investment Presentation Book for the Finance Committee Meeting of 12/4/2000, held in Miami, FL. Includes agenda, the minutes of the Finance Meeting of 9/10/2000, recent events, a portfolio summary, a market update by Cambridge Associates, and financial statements for the third quarter 2000.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2001 March 12 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        Agenda items include a recent events report, a portfolio summary report, and reports on the economic and market outlook for 2001. Also included are the minutes of the December 10, 2000 and March 12, 2001 meetings.
      - Special Finance Committee Meeting, London, 2001 May 8-9 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        The meeting concentrated on presentations and discussions relating to Knight Foundation's international investment program.
    - Governance Committee, 2006-2019; 6
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2006 September 11 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        Materials for the Governance (formerly Administrative and Human Resources) Committee include minutes of the June 12, 2006 meeting, a staffing update with organization chart, and a memo re: the Pension Protection Act of 2006 and the impact on Knight's plan. An amendment and board resolution for a change to the retirement plan is included.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2006 December 4 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        Materials for the Governance (formerly Administrative and Human Resources) Committee include minutes of the September 2006 meeting, a staffing update with organization chart, and memos re: Retirement Plan funding; and the 2007 budget.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2007 March 12 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        Materials for the Governance Committee include minutes of the March and December meetings, agenda, a staffing update with organization chart, and memos re: insurance and retirement programs.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2007 June 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Materials for the Governance Committee include minutes of the March meeting, agenda, a staffing update with organization chart, and a memo re: business travel and expense reimbursement. Also included are minutes of the June 4th meeting.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2007 September 16 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Materials for the Governance Committee include minutes of the June meeting, agenda, a staffing update with organization chart, and memos re: insurance and retirement policies. Also included is an update to the Foundation's conflict of interest policy.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2007 December 10 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Materials for the Governance Committee include minutes of the September and December meetings, agenda, a staffing update with organization chart, a proposed BOT resolution re: appointment of Trabian Shorters as VP/Communities Program; and memos re: retirement funding and the pension plan. Also included is the 2008 Budget Presentation.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2008 March 10 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        Materials for the Governance Committee include minutes of the December meetings, the agenda, a staffing update with organization chart, a proposed resolution re: retirement plan amendment #5 - request to rescind; memos re: trustees and officers liability insurance, 2007 pension plan activities and a general and administrative expense narrative for the 2007 December YTD actual vs. projected budgets.
      - Governance Committee Meeting (via teleconference), 2008 June 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        Materials for the Governance Committee, which took place one week before the Board of Trustees meeting, include minutes of the March meeting; the agenda; a staffing update with organization chart; three documents relating to the retirement plan: IRS favorable plan determination, lump sum restrictions for highly compensated employees, and the quarterly contribution; and the 2007 annual benefits management report. Also includes minutes for this meeting.
      - Governance Committee Meeting (via teleconference), 2008 September 8 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Materials for the Governance Committee, include minutes of the June meeting; the agenda; a staffing update with organization chart; a memo about indemnification, A resolution of the Board of Trustees approving an amendment to the articles of incorporation and By Laws of Knight Foundation, a memo re: Pension Plan 403 (b) restatement. Also includes minutes of the September meeting.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2008 December 8 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        Materials for the Governance Committee, held in Miami, include minutes of the September meeting; the agenda; a staffing update with organization chart;and the 2009 budget presentation, including memo, historical benchmarks, and G and A Analysis. Also included are the minutes of the meeting.
      - Governance Committee Meeting and Pension Investment Committee Meeting, 2009 March 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        Materials for the Governance Committee, held via teleconference, include minutes of the December meeting; the agenda; a staffing update with organization chart; general and administrative budget update; employee benefit plan and cost analyses; a joint report to the Governance and Investment committees on 2008 pension plan activities and a memo re: proposed change to the conflict of interest policy. Also included are the minutes of the March meeting, the ratified conflict of interest policy, and a resolution and updated retirement plan for KF employees. Also included are the minutes of the pension investment committee meeting, and a summary report on pension plan assets, investment performance and current asset allocation and a memo re: investment and design policy considerations for the retirement plan for KF employees.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2009 June 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2009 September 8 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        Materials for the Governance Committee, held via teleconference, include minutes of the June and September meetings; a staffing update with organization chart; and general and administrative budget update.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2010 March 8 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        Materials for the Governance Committee include minutes of the March and December meetings; a staffing update with organization chart; a memo re: lease proposal for KF offices, which was approved; employee benefits insurance renewals costs; and costs of new reorganization, with budget update.
      - Governance Committee Meeting, 2009 December 7 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Materials for the Governance Committee include minutes of the September meeting; a staffing update with organization chart; and the 2010 budget presentation, including budget memo, historical benchmarks, general and administrative budget analysis and direct charitable activities analysis. Admin expenses vs. Grants paid chart analysis. Also includes minutes of the meeting.